A Finding Aid to the Rudolph Schaeffer Papers, 1880s-1997, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1907-1988; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 1-2, OV 16
  - Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design Fund Raising Dinner, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Sannomiya, Miya, 1934-1958, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Shivram and Janaki, 1954-1964, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Society for Asian Art and "Treasures of the Orient" (exhibition), 1976-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Summer School of Decorative Art/Summer School of Creative Decoration (Rudolph Schaeffer with Douglas Donaldson), 1910s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Taxes, 1957-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Theatre for the World, San Francisco, 1956, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Thurman, Howard, 1959-1978, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Tobey, Mark, 1958-1977, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41-42)
  - Toor, Evelyn, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Weygers, Alexander G., 1955-1959, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - William Gaskin Memorial Lectures on Japanese Painting and Sculpture, 1970-1971, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Women's City Club Exhibition of Decorative Arts, 1929-1930, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Wood, Leona, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Women's City Club Exhibition of Decorative Arts, Installation Plans, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 16)
- Writings, circa 1910-1987; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 4.2 Linear feet Boxes 2-6, 15, 19, 21
  The series is arranged into 2 subseries:
  Missing Title
  4.1: Writings By Rudolph Schaeffer, circa 1910-1987
  4.2: Writings by Other Authors, 1923-1987
  - Writings by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1910-1987; 4.1; Archival Resource Key
    Writings by Rudolph Schaeffer include manuscripts for published and unpublished articles and drafts, notes, and manuscripts of several unpublished books including Collected Lectures of Rudolph Schaeffer on Color and Design, Color and Design, Prismatic Color Theory, and Rhythmo-Chromatics, all undated. Diaries include a volume recording Schaeffer's 1936 trip to Japan. 42 volumes of journals, compiled between 1954 and 1987 become progressively more introspective and focused on the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design. They contain entries on a wide range of subjects including lists of errands, invitation lists, class notes, drafts of letters, notes including staff assignments and staff meetings, autobiographical notes and reminiscences, and musings on religion and philosophy. Also extant are notes and texts for lectures and talks given at the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design and many other venues, as well as notes on philosophy, color, and miscellaneous topics.
    - Articles, 1918-1973, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - "Rhythmo-Chromatic Design and the Creative Process", 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Books (unpublished), Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
      - Collected Lectures of Rudolph Schaeffer on Color and Design, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Color and Design, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Prismatic Color Theory, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Rhythmo-Chromatics, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52-54)
    - Diaries, Archival Resource Key (Box 3)
      - Vol. 1: Japan, July 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
        Scope and Contents
        Oversized Volumes 2-3 housed in Box 15
    - Journals, Archival Resource Key (Box 3)
      - Oversize, Jan. 24 - Feb. 23, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Vol. 1:, Dec. 6, 1954 - Oct. 6, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Vol. 2:, Oct. 8, 1955 - Oct. 23, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Vol. 3:, Nov. 1, 1956 - Dec. 23, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Vol. 4:, Jan. 13, 1958 - Jan. 24, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Vol. 5:, Jan. 29, 1959 - Jan. 1, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Vol. 6:, Nov. 21, 1959 - May 2, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Vol. 7:, May 7 - Dec. 9, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Vol. 8:, Jan. 5 - July 2, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Vol. 9:, July 4, 1961 - Feb. 2, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Vol. 10:, Feb. 5 - Aug. 7, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Vol. 11:, Sept. 5, 1962 - March 26, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Vol. 12:, March 26 - Dec. 15, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Vol. 13:, Jan. 4 - Sept. 16, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Vol. 14:, Sept. 19, 1964 - May 18, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Vol. 15:, June 1, 1965 - March 29, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Vol. 16:, March 29, 1966 - Jan. 18, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Vol. 17:, Jan. 3, 1967 - Jan. 31, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Journal, Apr. 3 - May 5, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Vol. 18:, Feb. 12, 1968 - March 3, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Vol. 19:, March 8, 1969 - June 4, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Vol. 20:, March 4, 1969 - Jan. 19, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Vol. 21:, June 9 - Dec. 15, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Vol. 22:, Jan. 5, 1971 - Feb. 7, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Vol. 23:, Jan. 31 - Nov. 13, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Vol. 24:, Jan. 15 - May 14, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Vol. 25:, May 15 - Sept. 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Vol. 26:, Sept. 23, 1973 - Feb. 26, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Vol. 27:, March 4 - Dec. 16, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Vol. 28:, Jan 6 - Aug. 20, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Vol. 29:, Sept. 19, 1975 - March 11, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Vol. 30:, June 28, 1976 - March 29, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Vol. 31:, Aug. 10, 1977 - July 1, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Vol. 32:, Sept. 8, 1978 - Sept. 16, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Vol. 33:, Sept. 21, 1979 - May 12, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Vol. 34:, July 1980 - Dec. 1, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Vol. 35:, Jan. 19 - June 16, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Vol. 36:, Aug. 11, 1982 - Dec. 20, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Vol. 37:, Aug. 1 - Nov. 16, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Vol. 38:, Jan. 1 - March 16, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Vol. 39:, April 18 - Sept. 13, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Vol. 40:, Nov. 23, 1984 - Feb. 5, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Vol. 41:, Aug. 10, 1985 - Jan. 12, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Vol. 42:, March 29, 1986 - March 9, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Lectures, Archival Resource Key (Box 5)
      - Pre-dating Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, circa 1910, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Pre-dating Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, circa 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1920s-1980s, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23-39)
      - Oversize, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Other Venues, 1920s-1983, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 40-45)
    - Lists of Faculty and Staff, 1981-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, 1930-1984, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Notebooks, Archival Resource Key (Box 5)
      - Vols. 1-4, 1920, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Vol. 5 ("Quotations," "Basic Principles," "Application of Principles," Miscellaneous), 1935, 1979, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Notes on Color, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Notes on Philosophy, 1937-1944, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Notes, Miscellaneous, 1931, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Radio Talks, 1935-1952, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - School Catalog (draft), 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Oversized Vol. 2 and 3 from Box 3, Folder 1, Jan. - Aug., 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 15)
  - Writings by Other Authors, 1923-1987; 4.2; Archival Resource Key
    Writings by other authors are about Rudolph Schaeffer and his school. Included are reminiscences of former students, student essays, transcripts of oral history interviews conducted with Schaeffer, and Doris A. McMillan's notes of classes attended at the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design between 1923 and 1946.
    - Angelo, Ann B. "Rudolph Schaeffer: A Memoir (An Archival Image Applying Oral History Techniques)," M. A. Thesis, John F. Kennedy University (Museum Studies/Museology Program), 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Baglin, M. "Colour (one of R. Schaeffer's pupils looks at snow.)," Poem, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Cuddy, John. "The Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design - Which is in San Francisco,", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Lee, Chingwah. "Oriental Sculpture" provisional course outline, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - McMillan, Doris A. Class Notes, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1923-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10-12)
      Vol. 1: "Color and Form" with Rudolph Schaeffer
      Vol. 2: "Color" with Rudolph Schaeffer
      Vol. 3: "Color Notes" (from Light and Color by M. Luckish)
      Vol. 4: "Design" with Rudolph Schaeffer; "Plastic Form" with Rudolph Schaeffer; "Dyes" with Miss Henry and Welland Lathrop
      Vol. 5: "Plastic Form" with Rudolph Schaeffer; "Art in Public School" with Miss Lewis
      Vol. 6: "Aesthetic Appreciation" with Rudolph Schaeffer
      Vol. 7: "Flower Arrangement" with Rudolph Schaeffer; "Dyes and Application to Textiles" (research notes)
      Vol. 8: "Round the Color Wheel with Rudolph Schaeffer"; "Costume Design" with Marie Leonard
      Vol. 9: "Free Brush" with Rudolph Schaeffer; "Dimensional Design,"
    - Robbins, Beverly. Untitled Talk (about studying at the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, delivered at University of California Symposium), 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Roos, Robert de. "Rudolph Schaeffer,", circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Starbuck, Helen. Illustrated Book (tribute to Henry Schaefer-Simmern), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Student Essays, 1938, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Various Authors, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
      - Lectures, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1929-1948, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Press Releases (Rudolph Schaeffer and Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design), 1928-1950, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Welch, Nell True (edited by and foreword by Rudolph Schaeffer). Sunset's Flower Arrangement Book, circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Unknown. Poem, "An Abstract Principle Learned in Schaeffer's School of DESIGN,", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Deutsche Werkkunst: Arbeiten deutscher und österreichischer Künstler, 1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Chiang, Y. The silent traveller in San Francisco, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Artwork, 1911-1957; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 6, 15, 19, 21, OV 17
  Additional artwork, mainly drawings by Rudolph Schaeffer and others, is among the subject files (Series 3) and scrapbooks (Series 6).
  5.1: Artwork by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1911-1957
  5.2: Artwork by Other Artists, undated
  - Artwork By Rudolph Schaeffer, 1911-1957; 5.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Calligraphy, 1916, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Christmas Cards, 1927, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Color Studies (spiral bound volume), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Designs Illustrating Notan (with notes; on cards), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Designs, Drawings, Sketches, 1914-1957, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
      Oversized material housed in Box 15
    - Designs, Sketches and Notes (original collation, removed from 3-ring binder), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Sketchbooks, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
      - Vol. 1: Flower Arrangements (includes miscellaneous notes), 1939, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Vol. 2: Sketches (with notes), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Vol. 3: Furniture Designs, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Vol. 4: Sketchbook (with notes), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Oversized Designs and Drawings, and Furniture Designs from Box 6, Folder 24, 1911, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15)
    - Oversize Design Drawings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Artwork by Other Artists, 1915-1980, undated; 5.2; Archival Resource Key
    Artwork by others includes designs, probably by students including Enid Alpers, Mary A. Baird, and Margaret Paxton.
    - Designs, 1915, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Drawing (by Piercy), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Painting (by unknown), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15)
    - Drawing, "Perspective from Northwest Corner, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design?" (by J. B. Webb), 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 17)
    - Painted Student Drawings (fabric designs), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Three Miniature Watercolors by Henry W. Doane, circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Sketchbook by Arthur Sundberg, circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Album of Ceramics Photography and Portraits of Rudolph Schaeffer by Gail Reynolds Natzler, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Scrapbooks, circa 1924-1976; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 6, 14, 19
  Scrapbooks consist of 7 volumes containing printed material, photographs, letters, and a small amount of artwork. They document Rudolph Schaeffer's career, his school and former students, and the San Francisco art scene. Two volumes are devoted to specific subjects: the East-West Gallery (vol. 3, 1950), Rudolph Schaeffer's 90th Birthday and the 50th Anniversary of Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design (vol. 7, 1976).
  - Vol. 2, 1937-1943, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 32)
    Oversized Volume 1 is housed in Box 14
  - Vol. 3, East-West Gallery, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 33)
    Oversized volumes 4-6 housed in Box 14
  - Vol. 7, Rudolph Schaeffer's 90th Birthday and 50th Anniversary of the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Vol. 1, 1933-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
  - Vol. 4, Rudolph Schaeffer's 90th Birthday and 50th Anniversary of Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
  - Vol. 5, "Of passing interest and perhaps much more in 1971-1972,", Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
  - Vol. 6, "Of passing interest and perhaps much, much more,", 1973-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
  - Flower Arrangement Lectures - Fall 1940, Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - "Die Nibelungen" the film, circa 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Sound Recordings, 1949-1986; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1.8 Linear feet Boxes 11-13
  Recordings consist of audio cassettes and reels, along with a small number of transcripts. Most recordings are lectures by Schaeffer and others delivered at the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design. Other recordings include Rudolph Schaeffer playing the piano, and "Rudolph Schaeffer Day," a city-wide event in San Francisco commemorating Schaeffer's 100th birthday.
  The series is arranged into 3 subseries:
  7.1: Transcripts, undated
  7.2: Cassettes, 1979-1986
  7.3: Reels, 1949-1973
  - Transcripts, undated; 7.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Transcripts of Selected Recordings (1937-1980), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
  - Cassettes, 1979-1986; 7.2; Archival Resource Key
    - "Color" (parts 2-15), Lectures by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
    - "Rudolph;" "Rudolph Schaeffer Day;" "R. S. Piano," "R. S. at Home,", 1986, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Lectures (?) by Rudolph Schaeffer, March 24-May 12, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Reels, 1949-1973; 7.3; Archival Resource Key
    Unless otherwise noted, reels are 7".
    - "Art and General Semantics," Lecture by Chauduri, Feb. 16, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "Art in the Home" (parts 1 and 2), Lecture by William Gaskin, July 19, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Awareness," Lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, March 24, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "Awareness," Lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer (side 2), May 19; Art of Arrangement (course) Second Lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, Oct. 6, and Third Lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer ("Texture"), Nov. 3, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - "Beatnick Poetry," Lecture by Dr. Frederick Spielberg, Feb. 18, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Chinese Art Structure (summer course), Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - "Form, Color," July 26; Color and Revealing of Art Objects," July 27 (side 1); "Chinese Calligraphy and Its Influence on Chinese Painting," Lecture by William Wu, July 27 (side 2), 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - "Space," July 30; "Chinese Painters," Lecture by Howard Rogers, July 30; "Space, cont-d.," July 31; "Zen Bamboo Hall Prints," July 31, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - "Holistic Philosophy," Lecture by Dr. Chowdery, Aug. 1, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - "Finale," Aug. 3; "6 Courses of Chinese Art," Lecture by William Wu, Aug. 3, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - "Contemporary Weavers: Light and Life in Weaving" (exhibition and lecture), Rudolph Schaeffer and A. D., Jan. 9, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - "Fabrics and Fashions," Lecture by Hector Escabosa, July 11, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - "Interior Design - Fine Art, Space, Light," Lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, Oct. 1, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - "Japanese Rock Poems," Lecture by Dr. Frederick Spielberg, Oct. 15, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - "Picasso's Yoga," Lecture by Dr. Frederick Spielberg, March 19, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - "Plans for World Improvement,", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - "Principles of Design" (part 1), Lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, Oct. 29; "Elements of Design," Lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, Sept. 27 (first of a series on the Art of Design), 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Rudolph Schaeffer's Greeting to Students, Feb. 17, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - "School Image," Discussion among Rudolph Schaeffer, Bill Goghen, Bill Allen, Jo Sinel, and Fred Frey, March 6, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified Lecture by Ciampi (parts 1 and 2), July 26, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified Lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, Feb. 28, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified Lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer (transcribed Nov. 2, 1961), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified Lecture by Rudolph Schaeffer, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1905-1986; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Box 7, 19, 22
  Among the miscellaneous records are color samples for various Schaeffer projects and transcripts of various interviews conducted with Schaeffer and a meeting of the school staff. Guest books include those for Schaeffer's 99th and 100th birthday parties. Several matted Wiener Werkstätte fabic samples are also included.
  - Artifact - "Piece of colored stucco picked up from the ground, a specimen of beautiful blue green color, Peking, summer 1936"), Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Color Samples (for textiles, store and/or residential interiors, and unidentified purposes), 1947-1948 (3 folders); Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 2-4)
  - Guest Books, Archival Resource Key (Box 7)
    - Guest Book of Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1934-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Rudolph Schaeffer's 100th Birthday, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Rudolph Schaeffer's Birthday (loose pages), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Insurance Policies, 1905-1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Stock Certificate, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Transcripts, Archival Resource Key (Box 7)
    - Oral History of Rudolph Schaeffer interviewed by Margaretta K. Mitchell (Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley), 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Rudolph Schaeffer interviewed by Bernie Swadley, Oakland Museum, circa 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Staff Meeting, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, July 9, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Staff Meeting, Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, Dec. 1, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Matted Wiener Werkstätte fabric samples, circa 1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 19-22)
    - Oversize Matted Wiener Werkstätte fabric samples, circa 1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Student Award Certificate, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 23)
- Printed Material, 1906-1994; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 7-8, 19, 22
  Printed material concerns the career of Rudolph Schaeffer, his school and former students, the San Francisco art scene, and general art topics.
  Additional printed material is included with Series 3: Subject Files and Series 6: Scrapbooks.
  9.1: Produced by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1935-1942
  9.2: Produced by Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design, 1920s-1986
  9.3: Produced by Others, 1906-1987
  - Produced by Rudolph Schaeffer, 1935-1942; 9.1; Archival Resource Key
    Material produced by Schaeffer consists of articles and a book.
    - Articles, 1937-1938, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Books, Archival Resource Key (Box 7)
      - Flower Arrangement I (portfolio; photography by Ralph Young), 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14)